<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pramana's blog</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on pramana's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Pramana</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pr4-kp.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Now</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/now/</guid><description>Following the ideas behind a now page, I am&amp;hellip;
Going through my second year of undergrad. Building React apps in preparation for hackathons. Getting better at digital art, starting with anatomy. Learning a new program for video editing, Premiere Pro.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing prime spectrums with graphs</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/visualizing-prime-spectrum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/visualizing-prime-spectrum/</guid><description>In Atiyah and Macdonald&amp;rsquo;s book we construct a certain topological space from a ring called the prime spectrum of a ring. While working through the exercises, I saw an interesting way of viewing closed and open subsets of the prime spectrum that borrowed ideals from combinatorics.
What is the prime spectrum of a ring? Definition (Prime ideal). An ideal $\mathfrak{a}$ of a ring $A$ is a subring (a subset of $A$ that is still a ring under $A$&amp;rsquo;s operations) that has the property that any $a\in A$ times $p\in \mathfrak{a}$ has $ap\in \mathfrak{a}$ as well.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing horospheres on hyperbolic groups</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/horospheres-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/horospheres-project/</guid><description>This semester I was able to participate in our undergradute research lab, and, relevant to my past work, our project was in the field of geometric group theory. I plan on introducing our project and go over some topics in geometric group theory I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered before. This project was joint work with Noah Jillson and Katerina Stuopis with our advisors Daniel Levitin and Tullia Dymarz.
If you want to skip the mathematical jargon and see the results, skip to the end.</description></item><item><title>Weak solutions to dirichlet boundary problems</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/dirichlet-boundary-problems-weak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/dirichlet-boundary-problems-weak/</guid><description>For the final project in Analysis I, my professor asked us to write a paper on a topic adjacent to analysis. Being an applied mathematician, he recommended I study a very specific inequality called Gårding’s inequality.
If you would like to learn more about Gårding’s inequality itself, my paper has all the details about it, the prerequisites to understand it, and an application. In fact, most of the paper covers the necessary material needed to understand what the inequality is even saying (PDE analysis seems to be a lot less abstract than other fields, considering all the machinery I needed).</description></item><item><title>Group structures</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/group-structures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/group-structures/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Beachy and Blair&amp;rsquo;s Abstract Algebra Book, specifically their chapter on Group structure (7), and I wanted to summarize what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about group structures.
Finite groups and structure The problems and results derived from this chapter almost all concern with finite groups. We know a lot about finite groups. For example, we have this result:
Theorem (Burnside, 1904). Every group of order $p^a q^b$, where $p$ and $q$ are (not necessarily distinct) primes is solvable.</description></item><item><title>Graph ends and their purpose in geometric group theory</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/graphgroupends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/graphgroupends/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll give an intuition for how mathematicians define what graph ends are, and explain their use in geometric group theory. However, before I can do that, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what ends are in a graph theory perspective.
What are ends? The word ends is a little confusing, because they don&amp;rsquo;t really represent the &amp;ldquo;end&amp;rdquo; of a graph, at least not how we would define an end in real life. Think of a rope.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About this blog</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/about/</guid><description>👋🏽 Hello, and welcome to my website! I&amp;rsquo;m Pramana.
For the details of this site: I use Hugo with a modified Archie theme. This site is deployed through GitHub Pages. I&amp;rsquo;m always changing my mind on this blog&amp;rsquo;s design, so don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if there are changes here and there.
I have no commitment to a single subject for this blog. However, I do plan on keeping most posts math and computer science related.</description></item><item><title>course guide</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/courses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/courses/</guid><description>Some thoughts on UW courses. Inspired by this.
ANTHRO 105: Principles of biological anthropologybio credit ftw
MATH 475: Introduction to combinatoricsVery tedious course. Know how to use basic wolfram/python code and you will pass.</description></item><item><title>Notes</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/notes/</guid><description>MATH 522: Analysis II Notes (PDF) MATH 514: Numerical Analysis Notes (PDF) MATH 521: Analysis I Notes (PDF)(TeX) Final Paper – Gårding&amp;rsquo;s Inequality (PDF)(TeX) Abstract. This is an expository paper on the prerequisites for Gårding’s inequality. Proposed by Lars Gårding, this inequality has applications in the study of weak solutions to elliptic partial differential equations. We will give the prerequisites to state Gårding’s inequality and give one application. MATH 475: Introduction to combinatorics Notes (Chapter 14: Burnside&amp;rsquo;s Lemma and Polya Counting) (PDF) MATH 531 (UWM): Modern Algebra Notes (PDF)</description></item></channel></rss>