<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on pramana's blog</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on pramana's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Athul</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visualizing horospheres on hyperbolic groups</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/horospheres-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/horospheres-project/</guid><description>This semester I was able to participate in our undergradute research lab, and, relevant to my past work, our project was in the field of geometric group theory. I plan on introducing our project and go over some topics in geometric group theory I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered before.
If you want to skip the mathematical jargon and see the results, skip to the end.
Hyperbolic geometry Hyperbolic geometry is an important part of non-Euclidean geometry, where we study spaces that do not satisfy the postulates of Euclidean geometry.</description></item><item><title>Weak solutions to dirichlet boundary problems</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/dirichlet-boundary-problems-weak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/dirichlet-boundary-problems-weak/</guid><description>For the final project in Analysis I, my professor asked us to write a paper on a topic adjacent to analysis. Being an applied mathematician, he recommended I study a very specific inequality called Gårding’s inequality.
If you would like to learn more about Gårding’s inequality itself, my paper has all the details about it, the prerequisites to understand it, and an application. In fact, most of the paper covers the necessary material needed to understand what the inequality is even saying (PDE analysis seems to be a lot less abstract than other fields, considering all the machinery I needed).</description></item><item><title>Group structures</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/group-structures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/group-structures/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Beachy and Blair&amp;rsquo;s Abstract Algebra Book, specifically their chapter on Group structure (7), and I wanted to summarize what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about group structures.
Finite groups and structure The problems and results derived from this chapter almost all concern with finite groups. We know a lot about finite groups. For example, we have this result:
Theorem (Burnside, 1904). Every group of order $p^a q^b$, where $p$ and $q$ are (not necessarily distinct) primes is solvable.</description></item><item><title>Graph ends and their purpose in geometric group theory</title><link>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/graphgroupends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pr4-kp.github.io/posts/graphgroupends/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll give an intuition for how mathematicians define what graph ends are, and explain their use in geometric group theory. However, before I can do that, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what ends are in a graph theory perspective.
What are ends? The word ends is a little confusing, because they don&amp;rsquo;t really represent the &amp;ldquo;end&amp;rdquo; of a graph, at least not how we would define an end in real life. Think of a rope.</description></item></channel></rss>